Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series A: 5 x 7 inch negatives.
  - Pole vault, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 965)
    Negative no.A965. August 13, 1921. Image depicts a man participating in the pole vault, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. He has cleared the bar and has almost landed in front of it; his pole is falling backward. Another pole lies on the ground behind him. Three men in hats and white or striped shirts sit on the ground observing the vault, most likely officials of some kind. A large crowd of spectators watches in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 980, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 965 for print of this negative.
  - Start of the 220-yard dash, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 966)
    Negative no.A966. August 13, 1921. Image depicts four male runners at the start of the 220-yard dash, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The four men jump off the starting line as several officials on both sides look on. A large crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 966 for print of this negative.
  - Preliminary of the 100-yard dash, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 967)
    Negative no.A967. August 13, 1921. Image depicts four male runners finishing a preliminary heat of the 100-yard dash, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two have crossed the finish line; the third raises his arms in triumph (perhaps the top three finishers would move into the final); and the fourth is behind him. The group of men in straw hats on the right are probably officials of some sort. A large crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 967 for print of this negative.
  - 100-yard final, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 968)
    Negative no.A968. August 13, 1921. Image depicts male runners finishing the 100-yard dash, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. While the runner in the center with his arms raised may appear to be the winner, the presumed winner on the far left has already crossed the finish line. Two more runners can be seen. A large crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. The runner in the center appears to be the same man seen in Negative 969, in this box, the finish of the relay race. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 968 for print of this negative.
  - Relay race finish, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 969)
    Negative no.A969. August 13, 1921. Image depicts a man finishing the relay race (he also appears in Negative 968, in this box, the 100-yard dash final), most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man has crossed the finish line holding a baton in his right hand; another runner is behind him in the background. An official stands on the far right, while a crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 969 for print of this negative.
  - Girls race, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 975)
    Negative no.A975. August 13, 1921. Image depicts seven girls participating in a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. A crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course. It appears that there is another group of girls in the background, perhaps waiting to race. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 975 for print of this negative.
  - Push Ball contest, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 977)
    Negative no.A977. August 13, 1921. Image depicts two teams of men engaged in "Push Ball," most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The general idea seems to be to push the ball against your opponents, sort of like a reverse tug-of-war but involving a giant ball. A crowd of spectators watches from the side. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 978, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 977 for print of this negative.
  - Push Ball contest, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 978)
    Negative no.A978. August 13, 1921. Image depicts two teams of men engaged in "Push Ball," most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The general idea seems to be to push the ball against your opponents, sort of like a reverse tug-of-war but involving a giant ball. Note the men on the right rushing to help their team. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. The man in the foreground in a suit with his back to the camera is probably an official of some sort. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 977, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 978 for print of this negative.
  - Pole vault, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 980)
    Negative no.A980. August 13, 1921. Image depicts a man just clearing the bar of the pole vault, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Several men kneel or sit on the ground behind the bar, probably officials of some kind. Another competitor looks on as he kneels on the side on the right. Many spectators watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 965, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 1, Item 980 for print of this negative.
  - Back-to-Back contest, 1921 (Box 55, Folder 982)
    Negative no.A982. August 13, 1921. Image depicts four men participating in a back-to-back contest, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two teams of two men, each back-to-back, engage in some sort of race (one member of each team is walking backward). Note the man on the left in the clown costume. Spectators watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Box 54, Negative 963. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 2, Item 982 for print of this negative.
  - Quarter-mile boys race, 1921 (Box 55, Folder 986)
    Negative no.A986. August 13, 1921. Image depicts several boys participating in the quarter- mile boys race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. One boy has crossed the finish line, while two more can be seen behind him. Spectators line the side of the course. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 2, Item 986 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1921 (Box 55, Folder 987)
    Negative no.A987. August 13, 1921. Image depicts a man participating in the broad jump, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The men kneeling or sitting on the grass on either side of the jump are probably officials. Another competitor is sitting on the grass just to the left of the official in the dark suit. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 2, Item 987 for print of this negative.
  - High jump, 1924 (Box 58, Folder 1176)
    Negative no.A1176. August 1924. Image depicts a man participating in the high jump, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man is just clearing the high jump bar. Spectators, both male and female, watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 3, Item 1176 for print of this negative.
  - Stilt race, 1924 (Box 58, Folder 1177)
    Negative no.A1177. August 1924. Image depicts boys participating in a stilt race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Five boys can be seen racing on stilts; an official walks along the course on the right-hand side. Scattered spectators watch from the left-hand side of the course. Founders of the Draper Corporation, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 3, Item 1177 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1179)
    Negative no.A1179. August, 1924. Image depicts a group of boys engaged in a wheelbarrow race with spectators in background, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Each team consists of two boys, one of whom holds a set of wheels in his hands while his legs are held by the other boy, thereby forming a "human" wheelbarrow. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. Closely resembles Box 60, Negative 1207; see also Negative 1180, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1179 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1180)
    Negative no.A1180. August 1924. Image shows several young boys engaged in wheelbarrow race; spectators on sideline to left; young boy running alone on right. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1179, in this box, and Box 60, Negative 1207. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1180 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1181)
    Negative no.A1181. August 1924. Image shows a number of girls engaged in a potato race. Spectators in background; a male judge is standing on the right with his back to the camera. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1184, Negative 1185, Negative 1193, and Negative 1194, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1181 for print of this negative.
  - Boys' relay race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1182)
    Negative no.A1182. August 1924. Image shows four boys leaving the starting line with batons in their hands; three are in shirts, ties and caps and the fourth is in shorts and singlet. A few spectators (men and boys) can be seen mostly on the right. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1182 for print of this negative.
  - High jump, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1183)
    Negative no.A1183. August 1924. Image shows a young man in the middle of a high jump; spectators in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1183 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1184)
    Negative no.A1184. August 1924. Image shows a group of young girls engaged in a potato race; spectators in distance; several male judges are observing the action on the right. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1181, Negative 1185, Negative 1193, and Negative 1194, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1184 for print of this negative.
  - Spoon and potato race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1185)
    Negative no.A1185. August 1924. Image shows five girls engaged in race; one girl is wearing a hat (she can also be seen in Negative 1193, in this box). Girl in foreground has just dropped her potato in her box and is starting back to retrieve another. Spectators are scattered on the grass in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1181, Negative 1184, Negative 1193, and Negative 1194, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1185 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1186)
    Negative no.A1186. August 1924. Image shows approximately twelve girls engaged in a race; many spectators are in the background, a couple with umbrellas. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1186 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1187)
    Negative no.A1187. August 1924. Image shows a young man completing a broad jump; judges squatting on left to better observe length of jump; spectators behind them. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1190 and Negative 1191, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1187 for print of this negative.
  - Hurdle race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1188)
    Negative no.A1188. August 1924. Image shows two young men just clearing hurdles; a judge squats on the right to determine clearance; spectators on the left. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1189, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1188 for print of this negative.
  - Hurdle race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1189)
    Negative no.A1189. August 1924. Image shows two young men in the middle of jumping over the hurdles; racer on left has knocked down his hurdle; spectators on left; flagpole in center rear of image. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1188, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1189 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1190)
    Negative no.A1190. August 1924. Image shows young man at the moment of completing his jump-- his left foot ankle deep in sand. Two judges are squatting to observe his landing; spectators are behind them. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1187 and Negative 1191, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1190 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1191)
    Negative no.A1191. August 1924. Image shows young man at the moment of completing his jump-- both feet ankle deep in sand. Two judges are squatting to observe his landing; spectators are behind them. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1187 and Negative 1190, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1191 for print of this negative.
  - Pole race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1192)
    Negative no.A1192. August 1924. Image shows three teams of three boys each racing with a pole between their legs. Spectators in the background; a flagpole is in the center background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1192 for print of this negative.
  - Spoon and potato race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1193)
    Negative no.A1193. August 1924. Image shows four older girls engaged in race; two girls in foreground are approaching their boxes to drop in their potato, one wears a hat (she also appears in Negative 1185, in this box). Spectators are scattered on the grass in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1181, Negative 1184, Negative 1185, and Negative 1194, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1193 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1194)
    Negative no.A1194. August 1924. Image shows several girls; one is throwing her potato in the box and another is racing back to retrieve another potato. Several male judges are hunched over the boxes. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1181, Negative 1184, Negative 1185, and Negative 1193, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1194 for print of this negative.
  - The Norvelles [?], 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1195)
    Negative no.A1195. August 1924. Image depicts a team of two trapeze artists entertaining crowd of spectators in background and young children sitting on grass in foreground; young woman is on rings and her male partner is standing to left. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1196 and Negative 1197, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1195 for print of this negative.
  - The Norvelles [?], 1924 (Box 59, Folder 1196)